Guide to the Thompson Coit Elliott Papers 1903-1937
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
Thompson Coit Elliott Papers
1903-1937
Oregon Historical Society Research Library 1200 SW Park Avenue Portland, Oregon 97205 Phone: 503-306-5240 Fax: 503-219-2040 E-mail: libreference@ohs.org
Mss231
Elliott, T. C. (Thompson Coit), 1862-1943
2.5 cubic feet (5 document cases)
Papers of historian Thompson Coit Elliott who came west to Walla Walla, Washington in 1886. Includes correspondence, notes, copies of historical documents, speeches, published articles, and publication manuscripts on subjects relating to early exploration and trade in Inland Empire of the Pacific Northwest and the Oregon coast.
Biography of Thompson Coit Elliott:
Thompson Coit Elliott resided in Walla Walla, Washington, from 1886 until his death in 1943 at the age of 80. Born in Newington, Connecticut and educated at Amherst College in Massachusetts, Elliott traveled west and made his living as an investment banker. He married Anna A. Baker in Walla Walla in 1890.
T. C. Elliott's passion for history is revealed by an outpouring of historical publications, mostly in the Oregon Historical Quarterly and the Washington Historical Quarterly, and in his years of service on the board of directors of both the Oregon Historical Society and the Washington State Historical Society. Elliott was also an active member in the American Historical Association. He received honorary degrees from the University of Oregon and Amherst College, and an honorary membership from the British Columbia Historical Society. Elliot was also elected Fellow of the Royal Historical Society.
T. C. Elliott wrote widely on subjects relating to Pacific Northwest history. Much of his work focused on the early fur trade and explorations of the Inland Empire, with later work devoted to early contact along the Oregon coast. Although he principally wrote for historical publications, he did for a time pen a column in the Oregonian under the pseudonym C. T. Johnson. Elliott gave numerous public addresses and participated enthusiastically in community events celebrating local history. He was a member of the First Congregational Church, and a supporter of the Walla Walla public library and Whitman College.
This collection includes correspondence between T. C. Elliott and members of the historical profession, as well as other individuals with knowledge of historical events in his area of interest. Also included are Elliott's notes and copies of historical documents used in his research. Other correspondence relates to Elliott's book purchases for his extensive library, and to his involvement in history organizations and activities. A number of speeches, publication manuscripts, and published articles are also found in the historical subject files.
The collection is arranged into the following series:
Series A: Historical Subject Files, 1765-1936 and undated
Series B: Correspondence, 1908-1937
Series C: Ephemera, 1909, 1921, and undated
The collection is open to the public.
Gift of Thompson Coit Elliott, 1947. Library Accessions 229-319
"Biography- Elliott, T. C.," Vertical File, Oregon Historical Society Research Library, Portland.
Howay, F. W., "Thomson Coit Elliott, 1862-1943: A Tribute," Oregon Historical Quarterly 44: 228-31.
Powers, Alfred. History of Oregon Literature. Portland, OR: Metropolitan Press, 1935, pp. 550-52.
Davies, Barbara Coit Elliott. Interview by Charles Digregorio of Mrs. David Lloyd Davies. Portland, OR, 18 June 1976. SR 9372, Oregon Historical Society Research Library, Portland.
Elliott, T. C. Historical Papers and Addresses. Walla Walla, WA: T. C. Elliott, 1933.
The collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings:
Elliott, T. C. (Thompson Coit), 1862-1943 - Correspondence; Ermatinger, Edward, 1797-1876.; Ermatinger, Francis, 1798-1858.; Grant, Richard, 1794-1862.; Howay, Frederic William, 1867-1943 - Correspondence; Marshall, William I. (William Isaac), 1840-1906.; Meyers, Jacob A.; Newell, Robert, 1807-1869.; Ogden, Peter Skene, 1790-1854.; Simpson, George, Sir, 1786 or 7-1860.; Spalding, Henry Harmon, 1803-1874.; Thompson, David, 1770-1857.; Vancouver, George, 1757-1798.; Whitman, Marcus, 1802-1847.
United States. General Land Office; United States. Office of Indian Affairs; United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Oregon Superintendency; United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Washington Superintendency; Hudson's Bay Company.; North West Company.; Inland Empire Historical Society; Oregon Historical Society.
Columbia River - History; Idaho - History; Oregon - History; Spokane House (Wash.); Walla Walla (Wash.) - History; Washington (State) - History
Exploration and Discovery; Fur Trade; Indians of North America - Cayuse Indians; Indians of North America - Salish Indians; Indians of North America - Kalispel Indians; Indians of North America - Nez Percé Indians; Indian councils -- Washington (State); Indians of North America -- Oregon -- Wars; Bannock Indians -- Wars, 1878; Modoc Indians - Wars, 1873.; Nez Percé Indians Wars, 1877; Names, Geographical - Oregon; Overland journeys to the Pacific.; Ships - Jenny of Bristol; Whitman Massacre, 1847
Idaho; Oregon; Washington (State); Expeditions and Adventure; Native Americans; Overland Journeys to the Northwestern United States; Pacific Northwest History; Pioneers
Correspondence; Printed Ephemera; Manuscripts for Publication; Notes; Publications; Speeches
- Historical Subject Files., 1765-1936 and undated; Series A; 90 folders
  Historical research, copies of documents, and writings, and related correspondence to and from T. C. Elliott. Folders are Aarranged alphabetically by subject. Subject-related correspondence within each folder is arranged chronologically.
  List of Correspondents in Historical Subject Files:
  Amory, Copley
  Austin, John T.
  Bagley, C. B.
  Ballou, Howard M.
  Barrett, C. A.
  Barry, J. Neilson
  Baxter, P. L.
  Benoist, Theo.
  Benton, John H.
  Bridge, William D.
  Brosnan, Cornelius J.
  Brown, William C.
  Budd, Ralph
  Burgunder, Benjamin
  Burpee, Lawrence J.
  Campbell, John V.
  Cannon, Miles
  Coates, Grace Stone
  Coburn, C. P.
  Coyne, James H.
  Derr, A. R.
  Douglas, Walter B.
  Draper, Sarah Ogden
  Drumm, Stella M.
  Dye, Eva Emery
  Edwards, Charles A.
  Eels, Edwin
  Emmons, G. T.
  Ermatinger, C. O.
  Fisher, S. G.
  Fry, M. M.
  Hall, R. H.
  Hamilton, Gavin
  Harrison, J. Scott
  Hewen, H. W. B.
  Himes, George H.
  Hodder, Frank Heywood
  Holman, Frederick V.
  Howay, Frederic William
  Howell, J. A.
  Huston, S. B.
  Ivy, M. M.
  Jameson, J. Franklin
  Laut, Agnes C.
  Leeper, Robert D.
  Lengby, J. A.
  Lewis, William S.
  Lindenborn, W. E.
  Loomis, L. E.
  Macdonald, Duncan
  MacFarland, R.
  McIntyre, Annie E.
  Marshall, W. J.
  Martin, Archer
  Meany, Edmund S.
  Meyers, Jacob A.
  Minthorne, Richard
  Morice, A. G.
  Nichols, M. Leona
  Norman, Ben
  Ogden, Gerturde G.
  Ogden, Morris Meredith
  Parker, Will D.
  Parry, J. F.
  Partoll, Albert J.
  Pipes, Nellie B.
  Prosch, Thomas W.
  Pullman, John W.
  Redway, Jacques W.
  Reeder, George K.
  Rogers, Mary Cochrane
  Ryman, James H. T.
  Scholefield, E. O. S.
  Shaw, Albert
  Shaw, Frederick J.
  Shippee, S. B.
  Shoemaker, A. H.
  Siders, Walter R.
  Smith, E. D.
  Smith, Luther Ely
  Stenger, Eeliza
  Strong, James Clark
  Thompson, Francis A.
  Tiedt, W. J.
  Tombo, Rudolph, Jr.
  Tyler, Lyon G.
  Tyrell, J. B.
  Van Alstyene, Lawrence
  Watson, Robert
  Whealdon, Isaac H.
  Whiting, J. S.
  Winchester, Benjamin S.
  Young, Frederick G.
  - Barlow Road, 1913 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Bourbon, undated (Box-folder 1/2)
    Handscript memo on the name Bourbon and the Fort, Lake, and River "Bourbon."
  - Columbia River, undated (Box-folder 1/3)
    Typed notes on the discovery and mapping of the Columbia River.
  - Craig, William, 1855; 1874; 1908; and 1918 (Box-folder 1/4)
    Documents and correspondence regarding William Craig and his land claim. (See also Ward Massacre file.)
  - Crooks, Ramsey, undated (Box-folder 1/5)
    Notes on Ramsey Crooks' Letterbook. Crooks led the reorganized American Fur Company.
  - Day, John, 1914-1917 and undated (Box-folder 1/6)
    Notes and correspondence concerning the estate of John Day, hunter for the Pacific Fur Company and American Fur Company.
  - Douglas, Sir James and Alice Douglas, 1909 and undated (Box-folder 1/7)
    Excerpt from the life of Sir James Douglas, Hudson's Bay Company Chief Factor and Governor of Vancouver Island and the Crown Colony of British Columbia. Correspondence re:garding his daughter Alice Douglas's elopement. Poem, " Chief Douglass Daughter" with letters regarding concerning its authorship.
    Excerpt from the life of Sir James Douglas.
  - Duniway, Abigail Scott, 1852; 1956; and undated (Box-folder 1/8)
    Early writings of Oregon pioneer, publisher, and suffragette Abigail Scott Duniway. Journal of Crossing the Plains in 1852 of the family of John Tucker Scott (4 pages typescript). Journal of a Trip to Oregon, 1852 (102 pages typescript), written from notes taken on the journey (microfilmed as MSS 242).
  - Emmons, George F., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 1/9)
    Letters from G. T. Emmons to T. C. Elliott regarding George F. Emmons, a member of the U. S. Exploring Expedition, 1838-1842.
    George Emmons sailed aboard the Peacock, from which he surveyed and described Pacific harbors visited by the expedition.
  - Ermatinger, Edward and Francis, 1828-1859; 1912-1935 and undated (Box-folder 1/10)
    Copies of documents, notes, and research correspondence regarding Edward and Francis Ermatinger of the Hudson's Bay Company Columbia District. Includes copies of Edward Ermatinger's correspondence, primarily from John McLoughlin, John Work, and Archibald McDonald. Correspondence related to the Ermatinger papers in the hands of the County of Elgin.
  - Farnam, Russel, undated (Box-folder 1/11)
    Manuscript excerpt regarding fur trader Russel Farnam.
  - Flathead Indians, 1908-1914 (Box-folder 1/12)
    Corresondence regarding the Flathead Indian delegation to St. Louis, Missouri, ca. 1831, and the Flathead Medicine Tree.
  - Fort Hall, 1910-1918 and undated (Box-folder 1/13)
    Notes, documents, and correspondence related to the original site of Fort Hall.
  - Fort Walla Walla, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 1/14)
    Essay, poem, and correspondence regarding Hudson's Bay Company post Fort Walla Walla from J. S. Whiting of Seattle.
  - Fraser, Simon, 1808; 1924; and undated (Box-folder 1/15)
    Notes, document, and correspondence regarding fur trade explorer Simon Fraser, his journal, and his descent of the Fraser River.
  - Fur Trade, 1871; 1912; and 1915 (Box-folder 1/16)
    Correspondence, notes, and copies of documents regarding the fur trade in the Pacific Northwest. Pamphlet, "The Fur Trade in the Columbia River Basin Prior to 1811," address by T. C. Elliott, Pacific Coast Branch of the American Historical Association, Seattle, May 21, 1914.
  - Grant, Richard, 1834-1936 and undated (Box-folder 1/17)
    Documents (typescript copies), research notes, and correspondence regarding Richard Grant, his family, and Fort Hall. Autographed typescript of "Richard 'Captain Johnny' Grant, and Fort Hall on the Oregon Trail," by Frederick John Shaw, 1934. Two typed and hand annotated drafts of "Richard Grant."
  - Gray, Captain Robert, 1928-1929 and undated (Box-folder 1/18)
    Correspondence regarding Captain Robert Gray. Pamphlet: "Haswell's Log of Sloop Washington," introduction by T. C. Elliott.
  - Howes, Joseph, 1925 and undated (Box-folder 1/19)
    Correspondence and notes regarding Joseph Howes of the Hudson's Bay Company, Rocky Mountain House, and the mapping of Flathead Lake.
  - Hulbert, Archer Butler, undated (Box-folder 1/20)
    Tentative outline of "Overland to the Pacific: A Narrative and Documentary History of the Far West During the Great Half Century 1819-1869," edited by Archer Butler Hulbert (typescript carbon).
  - Hunt, Wilson Price, 1912 (Box-folder 1/21)
    Correspondence regarding Wilson Price Hunt, leader of the 1812 overland Astorian expedition to the mouth of the Columbia River.
  - Indian Councils -- Walla Walla -- I, 1930-1931 and undated (Box-folder 1/22)
    Research notes and correspondence regarding the Walla Walla Council of 1855 and related Indian treaties.
  - Indian Councils -- Walla Walla -- II, 1855 and undated (Box-folder 1/23)
    Photostat and typescript copies of council proceedings, treaties, and personal accounts and statements regarding the Walla Walla Council and treaties. Includes excerpts from the journal of secretary James Doty; statements of a Cayuse chief; the Nez Perce chief, Lawyer; Pe-pe-mox-mox; Umatilla chief, Owhi; and Joel Palmer.
  - Indian Councils -- Walla Walla -- III, 1855 (Box-folder 1/24)
    "A true copy of the Record of the Official Proceedings at the Council in the Walla Walla Valley held jointly by Isaac I. Stevens Gov Supt. W. T. and Joel Palmer Supt. Ind affairs O. T. on the part of the United States with the Tribes of Indians named in the Treaties made at that Council June 9th and 11th 1855" (typescript).
  - Indian Wars -- Bannock Piute War, undated (Box-folder 2/1)
    Handscript article by M. FitzGerald, "'Spokane Jack' Volunteers to Visit Camp of Hostiles to Dissuade Chief Egan from Going on the War-path."
  - Indian Wars -- Modoc War, 1917 (Box-folder 2/2)
    Correspondence regarding the Modoc War.
  - Indian Wars -- Nez Perce War, 1917-1934 (Box-folder 2/3)
    Correspondence regarding the Nez Perce War. Statement of the Nez Perce War by OWHI, 1919 (annotated typescript).
  - Jeffrey, John, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 2/4)
    Letter from R. Douglas of the Geographic Board, Canada, regarding Scottish botanist John Jeffrey.
  - Jenny and Ruby (ships) of Bristol, 1795; 1929; and undated (Box-folder 2/5)
    Correspondence and notes regarding the ships Jenny and Ruby of Bristol, England. Typescript copy of ship Ruby's commercial journal by Chas. Bishop, Commander, 1794-1795. Two typescript drafts of "The Jenny of Bristol: 1792-1794" by F. W. Howay and T. C. Elliott (published in the Oregon Historical Quarterly 30 (1929) as "Voyages of the "Jenny" to Oregon, 1792-94.")
  - Kittson, William, and family, 1827-1829; 1912; and undated (Box-folder 2/6)
    Correspondence, notes, and typescript copies of documents regarding William Kittson and his family.
    Flathead Indians delegation to St. Louis, Missouri
  - Kootenai House, 1912-1913; 1928; and undated (Box-folder 2/7)
    Correspondence and notes on the site of Kootenai House (also New Fort Kootenay) and on David Thompson's itinerary (1809-1812). Address by Basil G. Hamilton before the Wilmer Improvement Society, May 1912.
  - Kullyspell House, 1915-1928 and undated (Box-folder 2/8)
    Correspondence and notes regarding Kullyspell House and David Thompson. (see also file on Kootenai House) Typescript excerpts from journal, attributed to Thompson (1809-1812). (See also Spokane House and David Thompson files.)
  - Lewis, Meriwether, 1806 (Box-folder 2/9)
    "Sketch of Captn. Lewis's Voyage to the Pacific Ocean by the Missesourri [sic] Columbia Rivers from the States of America," 1806 (typescript copy).
  - MacKenzie, Alexander, 1824-1825; 1911-1915 and undated (Box-folder 2/10)
    Correspondence and memorial address (2 copies; draft and possible final copy) regarding explorer Alexander MacKenzie. Documents relating to Columbia, Fraser, and Lewis Rivers (1824-1825); extracts from 1825 journal of Alexander McKenzie (photostat copies).
  - MacKenzie, Donald, 1822; 1912-1921; and undated (Box-folder 2/11)
    Correspondence, articles, and copy of document related to fur trader Donald MacKenzie.
  - McDonald, Angus, 1838-1855; 1907-1930; and undated (Box-folder 2/12)
    Correspondence, copies of documents, and research notes regarding Hudson's Bay Company chief trader Angus McDonald and family.
  - McDonald, Archibald and Ranald McDonald, 1830-1839; 1909-1919; and undated (Box-folder 2/13)
    Correspondence, notes, and documents (handscript, typescript, and photostat copies) relating to Hudson's Bay Company chief factor Archibald Mc Donald and his son Ranald McDonald. Reprint of "Archibald McDonald: Biography and Genealogy" by William S. Lewis.
  - McDonald, Finnan, 1827-1836; 1922-1925; and undated (Box-folder 2/14)
    Correspondence, notes, and typescript copies of documents relating to Finnan McDonald of the Northwest Company and Hudson's Bay Company. "'Finn McDonald' Explorer, Fur Trader and Legislator," by J. A. Meyers, 1922 (typescript). Handwritten and typewritten draft manuscripts of "The McDonalds of Oregon: Big Finnan The Grand" by T. C. Elliott and John A. Chisolm.
  - McDonald, John, of Garth, 1859; 1923 (Box-folder 2/15)
    Typescript copy of autobiography of John McDonald of Garth, and correspondence regarding the document.
  - McKay, Alexander and Thomas McKay, 1934-1935 and undated (Box-folder 2/16)
    Correspondence and notes regarding Alexander McKay and his son Thomas.
  - McKinlay, Archibald, 1846; 1882 (Box-folder 2/17)
    Document and correspondence regarding Archibald McKinlay, chief trader of the Hudson's Bay Company post, Fort Walla Walla.
  - McLeod, John, 1825-1837; 1909 (Box-folder 2/18)
    Handscript and typescript copies of documents relating to John McLeod, Sr., chief trader of the Hudson's Bay Company. Correspondence regarding copies.
  - McLoughlin, John and Marguerite Wadin McKay McLoughlin, 1803-1842; 1917; 1934-1935; and undated (Box-folder 2/19)
    Correspondence to and from T. C. Elliott regarding the McLoughlin and Wadin families, typescript copies of documents, and typescript draft manuscripts by T. C. Elliott. John McLoughlin was chief factor of Fort Vancouver and founder of Oregon City.
  - Minthorne Family, 1919 (Box-folder 2/20)
    Correspondence with Richard Minthorne regarding the Minthorne [Minthorne] family of the Whitman Mission and Umatilla Indian Reservation.
  - Miscellaneous Notes from Conversations, 1910-1920 and undated (Box-folder 2/21)
    Notes from T. C. Elliott's conversations with Barry Burgunder, Charles Clark, and H. E. Johnson on assorted topics not addressed in other subject research files.
  - Miscellaneous Notes from Written Sources, undated (Box-folder 2/22)
    T.C. Elliott's notes on topics not clearly related to those of the subject files.
  - Newell, Robert, 1908 (Box-folder 3/1)
    Correspondence regarding Robert Newell, his land holdings, and his work as Agent for the Nez Perce Indians.
  - Nisqually House, 1833-1835 and undated (Box-folder 3/2)
    Journal of Occurrences at Nisqually House, From May 30th, 1833, to April 25th, 1835 (87 page typescript).
  - Ogden, Peter Skene -- Correspondence regarding, 1866; 1908-1931 and undated (Box-folder 3/3)
    Letters to and from T. C. Elliott regarding Hudson's Bay Company expedition leader and chief factor Peter Skene Ogden and his family. Includes a handscript letter, reportedly from Peter Ogden, son of Peter Skene Ogden, to William R. Smith of the Red River settlement, 1 September 1866.
  - Ogden, Peter Skene -- Article by T. C. Elliott, 1910 and undated (Box-folder 3/4)
    Typescript draft with handwritten notations and published reprint of "Peter Skene Ogden: Fur Trader" by T. C. Elliott, which was published in the Oregon Historical Quarterly, volume 11 (1910).
  - Ogden, Peter Skene -- Research notes, 1817-1909 and undated (Box-folder 3/5)
    Research notes and typescript and handscript copies of documents pertaining to the life of Peter Skene Ogden. Includes some notes on Ogden family genealogy and Ogden's estate.
  - "Oregon Expedition", 1832 (Box-folder 3/6)
    Typescript copy of article appearing in the Missouri Republican, 14 February 1832, on the subject of a proposed expedition to send settlers to Oregon, then a politically disputed territory.
  - Oregon -- Origin of Name -- Jonathan Carver, 1766-1786; 1921-1922 (Box-folder 3/7)
    Correspondence and handscript copies of documents relating to Jonathan Carver and the name "Oregon." Includes excerpts from Journal of the Travels of Jonathan Carver in the Year 1766 and 1767 and Memoirs of John Fothergill, M.D.C. by John Coakley Lettsom, 1786.
  - Oregon -- Origin of Name -- Richard Rogers, 1765-1775; 1921-1929 and undated (Box-folder 3/8)
    Correpsondence and handscript and typescript copies of documents relating to Richard Rogers and the name "Oregon." Includes Rogers' Proposal and Petition to the British king to seek a northwest passage through North America, and "Instructions and Orders to James Stanley Goddard" 1766.
  - Palmer, Joel, 1845-1846 and undated (Box-folder 3/9)
    Typescript excerpts of Joel Palmer's journals of 1845-1846, and of Peter H. Burnett's "Recollections and Opinions of an Old Pioneer."
  - Patterson, J. F. (Fred), 1861-1866; 1929; and undated (Box-folder 3/10)
    Typescript and handscript copy of documents, correspondence, notes, and newspaper clipping regarding the crimes and assassination of J. F. (Fred) Patterson in Walla Walla, Washington, 1866.
  - Pelly, J. H., 1838; 1916 (Box-folder 3/11)
    Copy of a letter from J. H. Pelly, Governor of the Hudson's Bay Company, to the Lords of the Committee of Privy Council for Trade, 7 February 1838 (12 page typescript).
  - Pendleton, Oregon, undated (Box-folder 3/12)
    Recollections of Z. F. Moody, addressed to the President of the Umatilla Historical Society, Pendleton (3 page typescript).
  - Pike, Zebulon Montgomery, 1805 (Box-folder 3/13)
    Copy of letter from Zebulon Pike to Hugh M'Gillis, 6 February 1805 (5 page typescript).
  - Prevost, J. B., 1813-1818; 1918; and undated (Box-folder 3/14)
    Correspondence to and from T. C. Elliott, notes, and copies of documents relating to United States Commissioner J. B. Prevost and the surrender of the Fort George (Astoria) in 1818.
  - Red River Settlement, 1909 and undated (Box-folder 3/15)
    Correspondence and notes regarding schools and religious activity at the Red River Settlement.
  - Revet, Francois, 1838-1866; 1933 (Box-folder 3/16)
    Correspondence and documents regarding fur trappers Francois and Antoine Rivet and their families, and the estate and land holdings of Francois Rivet. (Rivet is also spelled Rive, Rivet, Revais, and Reve.)
  - Roads -- Washington Territory, 1901; 1912 (Box-folder 3/17)
    Correspondence regarding old roads in Washington Territory. Copy of "Something about Fording Rivers in Pierce and Thurston Counties in Washington Territory between 1850 and 1890" by E. Higgins, Ft. Nesqually, Aug. 1st, 1901 (3 page typescript).
  - Ross, Alexander, 1824 and undated (Box-folder 3/18)
    Typescript excerpts of explorer Alexander Ross's journal, 1824, and annotations and editorial notes by T. C. Elliott.
  - Salish House, 1914; 1923 (Box-folder 4/1)
    Correspondence concerning the Hudson's Bay Company outpost Salish House, Thompson Falls, and environs.
  - Scarborough, James Allan, 1910 and undated (Box-folder 4/2)
    Correspondence and notes regarding James Allan Scarborough, Hudson's Bay Company employee on the Columbia and Puget Sound, his residence and family.
  - Simpson, Sir George, 1847-1848; 1918-1930; and undated (Box-folder 4/3)
    Copies and excerpts of documents authored by Sir George Simpson, Governor of the Hudson's Bay Company, including 24 June 1848 letter to Archibald McKinlay. Correspondence to and from T. C. Elliott regarding Governor Simpson and his family. Notes regarding Simpson family genealogy.
  - Sinclair, James, and William Sinclair, 1913-1936 and undated (Box-folder 4/4)